Okay.
好
I'm moving out, so you're in charge of paying the rent.
我要搬過去，房租就給你繳了
-When's it due? -On the first.
也對，什麼時候要繳？ 1號
And that's every month?
每個月嗎？
No, just the months you want to live here.
不是，你想住的月分才要繳
Okay, here's the phone bill.
這是電話費
Oh, my God!
天哪
That's our phone number.
那是電話號碼
I know I kind of sprung this me-moving-out-on-you thing.
是我突然決定要搬走的
-Why don't I cover you for a while? -No way!
所以我先幫你擋一陣子吧 不行
Joey Tribbiani does not take charity...
喬伊崔比亞尼不接受施捨…
anymore.
再也不了
-It's not charity, Joe. -Forget it.
這不是施捨… 不行，別再說了
Thanks, but I'm done taking money from you.
謝謝，但我不想再拿你的錢了
I can take care of myself. What's next? Come on.
我可以照顧自己，還有什麼？
Here's the electric bill.
這是電費
-This is how much we pay for electric? -Well,yeah.
用個電要這麼多錢？ 對
So we'll do the rest of the bills later,then?
其他的帳單待會再看羅？
The One On The Last Night
本集播出：「最後一夜」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Will Joey have to give up the apartment?
那喬伊得搬出去嗎？
I offered him money, but he wouldn't take it.
希望不用 我想給他錢，但是他不收
How much does he need?
你覺得他需要多少？
$1500 would cover him for a few months...
我想1千5應該夠他活幾個月
but I have to trick him into taking it so I don't hurt his pride.
但我得騙他收下 免得傷害他的自尊
Why don't you hire him as an actor?
你怎麼不雇他當演員？
You could have him dress up and put on skits whenever you want.
你可以叫他扮裝演短劇 怎樣都行
Well, that would help the pride thing.
那樣對自尊確實有幫助
Wow, you look great! Do you wanna move in with me tomorrow?
你真是水噹噹 明天要不要搬來跟我住？
好啊 好
Any plans for tonight?
你們女生今晚要做什麼？
Instead of being sad on my last night with Rachel...
與其難過我和瑞秋要分開
we're going out to celebrate Rachel's moving in with Phoebe.
我們不如去吃飯慶祝 瑞秋搬去跟菲比住
-And also my birthday. -It's not your birthday.
還有我的生日 今天不是你的生日
What a mean thing to say! I'd never tell you it wasn't your birthday.
這樣講好惡劣 我就不會戳破你
You guys have anything planned for the big last night?
你們男生有什麼節目嗎？
Instead of just hanging out, we figure we'd do nothing.
與其一起打混 我們決定什麼也不做
Knicks' season opener tonight. I thought you'd come and watch it.
今晚是尼克隊首戰 我以為你們會想來我家看
I don't know,Ross.
不知道耶
Not if you talk about how you gave up basketball to become a paleontologist.
我怕你又吹說你放棄打球 去當古生物學家
I did give up a career in basketball to become a paleontologist!
我本來就放棄打球 去當古生物學家
-Phoebe.. -You're not dressed yet?
菲比，我在想… 你還沒換衣服？
We're supposed to start having fun in 15 minutes!
我們15分鐘後就要去玩了
And clearly, not a minute sooner.
而且早1分鐘都不行
You are packed,though, right? Please tell me you're packed?
你都打包好了吧？拜託你說是
Of course I'm packed. Monica,relax.
我當然打包好了，你別緊張
I wanted to ask Phoebe what I should wear.
我只是想問菲比我該穿什麼
My God,I can't get a minute of peace.
天哪，我真是一刻也不得閒
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
Monica's just gonna kill you.
摩妮卡會宰了你
I know.
我知道
What you're wearing is fine for that.
你穿這樣蠻適合慘死的
瑞秋，我要借…
You're not packed!
你沒打包！
You're not packed even a little bit!
你根本沒打包
Surprise!
驚喜
Don't get mad, because this is what happened.
什麼？ 你別發飆，是這樣的
I started packing, then I realized,"What am I doing?"
我開始打包 然後想到：我在幹嘛？
I am lousy at packing,right?
我最不會打包了，對吧？
But you love packing!
但你最愛打包了
So as a gift to you on our last night....
所以做為我的臨別贈禮…
I'll be coordinator!
我可以當總指揮
Oh, my God, I'm so sorry. I didn't get you anything.
對不起，我沒幫你準備禮物
Everybody has to help. Phoebe, can you help?
大家都要幫忙 菲比你可以幫忙吧？
I have plans.
我有事
-You have plans with us. -That's right.
你是跟我們有約 沒錯
Chandler can make boxes, Ross can wrap and Joey can lift.
錢德可以帖紙箱，羅斯封箱 喬伊搬東西
Tell the guys they have to help out.
菲比，去通知男生幫忙 好
My God,thank you!
天哪，謝謝你
Monica's gonna make you pack! She's got jobs for everyone!
快逃，摩妮卡要叫你們收東西 她把工作都分好了
Now, it's too late for me, but save yourselves!
我是躲不掉了，你們快逃
The movers will be here in 11 hours. Rachel hasn't packed.
搬家公司11個小時後會來 瑞秋還沒打包
Now, everybody has to help. Chandler..
每個人都得幫忙 錢德
I have plans with Joey.
我和喬伊有事
-You said you were doing nothing. -Yes,but for the last time.
你不是說你們沒事？ 這是最後一次了嘛
Fine. Now,Ross..
好吧，羅斯…
-I can't do it. -Why not?
我沒辦法幫忙 為什麼？
-Don't you have Ben? -Because I have Ben!
班要來 因為班要來
It's almost past his bedtime. Where is he?
都快8點了，他都快上床了 他在哪裡？
He's at a dinner party.
他去參加晚宴
He's really coming? I can see in your apartment.
他真的要來？我看得見你家喔
Of course he is. What?
當然是真的
You think I'd use my son as an excuse?
難道我會拿兒子當藉口？
What kind of father do you think I am?
你把我當成哪種爸爸？
All right. Sorry.
好吧，對不起
I gotta go make a fake Ben.
我得做個班的人偶
Here it is.
來了
Our last pizzas together as roommates.
室友時代最後的披薩
I wish I knew that. I ordered Chinese.
我不知道你會買披薩 我叫了中國菜
Well,that's okay.
沒關係
In a way it's kind of nice. You know?
其實這樣蠻好的
Our last dinner together. Me, bringing the food of my ancestors...
我們最後的兩人晚餐 我帶我祖先的食物
you,the food of yours!
你帶你祖先的食物
I had an idea for what to do on our last night.
喬伊，我有個比較奇怪的想法
What do you say we play a little foosball for money?
我們來打幾盤賭錢如何？
Are you crazy? You haven't beaten me since my injury-plagued '97 season.
你瘋啦？自97年傷後復出 你就沒贏過我
-It'd be easier to give me your money. -Yes, it would.
你拿錢送我還比較快 是啊
What do you say to $50?
你覺得50元如何？
I say to it: "50 dollars,you are more than I have."
我會對它說 50元，你比我的財產還多
If you know that you'll win, what difference does it make?
既然知道會贏，為什麼不賭？
-You're on. -Okay,let's play.
好，賭了 好，開賽
The big game. Italy versus...
世紀之戰，意大利對…
China, apparently.
當然是中國隊
Look,it's the Rollerblades.
看，是直排輪鞋
Oh,God!
天哪
You remember when we got these?
記得我們什麼時候買的嗎？
不記得
I guess you weren't there.
那你應該不在
You guys, we said we were gonna have fun.
喂，我們說過要開心的
Come on. Hey, remember the time....
別這樣，記不記得那次…
You don't remember?
你們不記得嗎？
Sorry,Phoebe. I'm just really sad that I'm leaving.
對不起，要搬走我真的很難過
I'm gonna miss you so much.
我會很想你
This doesn't have to be so sad, though,you know?
其實不必這麼難過
Instead of thinking about how you'll miss each other...
別再想你們會想念對方了
you should think of the things you're not gonna miss.
想想你們不會懷念的事
I don't think there's anything.
我覺得沒有
Come on,there's gotta be something.
總會有一兩件
She's perfect.
沒有，她太完美了
I have one.
我有一件
Okay, you can go first.
很好，你先說
I guess I'm not gonna miss the fact...
我不會想念
that you're never allowed to move the phone pen.
你不准我把留言筆拿走
That's a good one. Okay, Monica, anything?
說得好，摩妮卡，你有嗎？
You know, does Rachel move the phone pen?
瑞秋會把留言筆拿走嗎？
Sometimes.
有時候會
Always, actually.
其實每次都會
There you go. Doesn't everyone feel better?
這就對了，這樣不是好多了？
Not just the phone pen.
不只是留言筆
I never get my messages.
我老是收不到留言
You get your messages.
你收到啦
It doesn't count if you have to read them off your hand...
趁你在沙發上睡著
after you've fallen asleep on the couch.
去看你的手背應該不算
So you missed a message from who? Chandler?
那你是沒接到誰的留言？ 錢德？
Or your mom?
還是你媽？
Or Chandler?
還是錢德？
Or your mom?
還是你媽？
It worked! No one's sad!
太好了，成功了，沒人難過了
I win again!
萬歲！我又贏了
That's,like, 500 bucks you owe me!
你已經欠我5百了
Man! Five hundred dollars.
5百美金
That is a lot of electricity,huh?
值很多電
I gotta buy some food.
我得買點吃的
Give me a chance to win my money back. Sudden death...
給我撈本的機會 驟死賽
one goal,$1000.
一球…1千
-You serious? -Yes!
真的？ 當然
Get ready to owe me.
好，準備欠我錢吧 好
Here we go. Ready?
來吧，好了嗎？
No...
不~~
one can beat me!
要想贏我
That's why only the little fake men are supposed to do the kicking.
看吧，所以只有小假人 可以出腳
Hi, Ross. See, other people call me!
羅斯…看吧，還有別人會打來
Oh, your brother. Score!
你老哥，了不起
What's up?
怎樣？
I'm here with Ben.
我跟班在一起
Thought we'd say hi.
想跟你問個好
-Put him on. -Ben,say hi to Aunt Monica.
叫他聽 班，跟摩妮卡姑姑打招呼
I guess he doesn't feel like talking right now.
看來他現在不想說話
He's smiling,though.
不過他在笑
Okay, talk to you later.
好，待會再聊
You know, Daddy was gonna be a basketball player.
爸爸本來要去打籃球的
I think it was better when you guys were sad.
我覺得你們難過時比較好
Hey, remember the Rollerblades?
記得這雙直排輪鞋嗎？
You know what else I won't miss? "I'm Monica.
你知道我還不會想念什麼？ 我是摩妮卡
I wash the toilets 17 times a day, even if people are on it!"
我一天刷十七次馬桶 有人在上也照刷
"Hi,I'm Rachel. Is my sweater too tight?
我是瑞秋 我的毛衣太緊了嗎？
I'd better wash it and shrink it!"
不會？那我得洗一洗讓它縮水
"I'm Monica. I never get messages from interesting people."
我是摩妮卡 都沒有有趣的人留言給我
I call her.
我會打給她
"Oh, my God! I love Ross. I hate Ross. I love Ross. I hate Ross!"
天哪！我愛羅斯，我恨羅斯 我愛羅斯，我恨羅斯
"My God! I can't find a boyfriend.
天哪！我交不到男朋友
I'll stumble across the hall and sleep with the first guy I find there!"
乾脆到對面去看到誰就上誰
You guys, come on, this is the last night!
拜託啦，都最後一夜了
Yeah,you're right, and so for the last time I would like to ask you:
你說得對 所以我再說最後一次
Boo-hoo. Get out of my room!
滾出我的房間
We should get a move on if we want to make those dinner reservations.
如果想趕去餐廳就得快了
Still broken?
還是壞的？
It sucks,man.
真是爛透了
Your last night,and I lose the two most important things:
你在這裡的最後一晚 我卻失去兩樣最重要的東西
The foosball table...
足球檯
and $500.
和5百元
There are other ways to win back your money. How about blackjack?
有別的辦法可以把錢贏回去 要不要玩二十一點？
Not my game.
我不喜歡那個
You know what? We can play a new game.
那就玩… 我們可以玩個新遊戲
-It's fun! -What's it called?
很好玩 叫什麼名字？
Cups.
杯牌
-I don't know how. -I'll teach you. It's easy and fun.
我不會玩杯牌 我教你，來嘛，簡單又好玩
-All right. -Here you go.
好吧 好，拿牌
I have two queens. What do you have?
我有兩張皮蛋，你呢？
-A 2 and a 5. -You win! Fifty dollars!
二和五 你贏了，50元
-Really? -Let's play again.
真的？ 沒錯，再玩
-What have you got? -4 and a 9.
你是什麼牌？ 四和九
You're kidding,right?
不會吧？
-No. Why? -That's a full cup!
怎麼了？ 那是滿杯
Damn, I am good at Cups!
我真是杯牌高手
I'm not talking to her.
我不要跟她說話
You have to take the first step...
總得有人先開口
because she's the one who's leaving. It's harder for her.
這個人應該是你 因為她要搬走，她比較難過
Maybe you're right.
也許吧…
But she made fun of my phone pen!
但她嘲笑我的留言筆
I know. I took it hard too.
我知道，我也覺得很過分
She's in there right now, crying. I can hear her.
她正在裡面哭，我聽得見
She's not crying.
她沒有在哭
She's holding it in. She's so brave. Go.
她正在忍，真勇敢，快去吧
I feel bad about what happened..
瑞秋，剛才的事我很…
-What are you doing? -I'm unpacking.
你在幹什麼？ 把東西拿出來 什麼？
I'm not moving. Is that picture straight?
我不搬了，這幅畫正嗎？
It needs to go about 20 blocks to the left.
離左邊差了十萬八千里
You're the one who wants this big change and to move in with Chandler!
你知道嗎？ 是你要改變，跟錢德同居
You should go! Why do I have to leave?
你才應該走，為什麼要我走？
-It's my apartment! -It's mine too! What else you got?
因為這是我的房子 它也是我的，還有呢？
How about: You're moving!
還有就是你要搬出去
This is ridiculous.
這樣太可笑了
We should be packing you!
我們應該幫你打包
-Hey, how you guys doing? -Great. Monica's moving.
你們談得怎樣？ 很好，摩妮卡要搬走
I am not!
我才沒有
Really? How come all your stuff is in this box?
是嗎？那為什麼你的東西 都在這個箱子裡？
Okay, you guys, I think I know what's going on here!
好，我知道是怎麼回事了
You guys? Stop!
喂…停
I know you're acting mad because it'll make it easier to leave.
你們是假裝生氣，以免捨不得
But deep down,you're really sad. Deep,deep down.
其實內心深處你們還是很難過
-No, Phoebe, I am mad! -Well,deep deep deep down!
不，我很生氣 最最最深處
I'm just mad.
我就是很生氣
Then keep running.
那就繼續追吧
You win!
你贏了
-What did you have? -Nothing beats...
你是什麼牌？ 不重要 什麼都比不上...
a three and a six.
三和六
That, my friend, is "D Cup."
那叫D罩杯
How much have you won so far?
你目前為止贏了多少？
-700. -Not 700 exactly?
哇，7百 不是正好7百吧？
Double it.
再加7百
In Cups, once you get $700, you have to double it.
在杯牌裡，一旦贏到7百 就得自動加碼
I didn't make up the rules.
規則又不是我訂的
Now, after you receive the doubling bonus, you get one card.
拿到加碼獎金後 你可以拿一張牌
That one card could be worth $100, which brings your total to $1500.
那張牌有可能值1百元 讓你總共贏得1千5
Don't get excited, that won't happen unless you get the.. No way!
別太興奮，除非你拿到… 不會吧
This is the last box of your clothes.
這是最後一箱衣服
I'm just gonna label it "What were you thinking?"
我會在上面註明 「你在想什麼？」
I was just gonna go across the hall and write that on Chandler.
有意思，我正想到對面 在錢德身上那樣寫
Guys, I don't wanna make things worse, but...
兩位，不是我想雪上加霜
I don't wanna live with Rachel anymore.
但我不想跟瑞秋住了
-What? -You're so mean to each other.
什麼？ 你們對對方好壞
I don't wanna end up like that with Rachel. I still like you.
我不想跟瑞秋翻臉 我還是喜歡你
That's fine because I'm not moving.
沒關係，因為我不搬了
Phoebe, you gotta take her.
菲比，你一定要收留她
I said some bad stuff...
我說了很多她的壞話
but Rachel has qualities that make her a good roommate.
但瑞秋也有一些好室友的特質
Like what, Monica?
是嗎？像什麼？
She has 147,000 pair of boots.
她有幾千雙靴子
Good start,Mon.
真是個好的開始
She lets you borrow them.
她會借給你穿
And you stretch them out with your big old clown feet.
然後你再用你的大腳把它撐大
Do you wanna live outside? Because it's getting cold!
你想睡路邊嗎？天氣要變冷羅
She gets tons of catalogs and folds down the pages of things I'd like.
她有一大堆目錄 她會把我會喜歡的部分折起來
What else?
還有呢？
When I take a shower...
我洗澡時
she leaves me notes on the mirror.
她會在鏡子上留言給我
I do. I do do that.
那倒是
That's nice. I like having things to read in the bathroom.
真好 我喜歡浴室裡有東西可讀
When I fall asleep on the couch...
我在沙發上看書看到睡著
she covers me with a blanket.
她會幫我蓋毯子
Well,you know, I don't want you to be cold.
我不希望你冷到
And when I told her I was gonna move in with Chandler...
當我說我要跟錢德同居時
she was really supportive.
她非常支持我
You were so great.
你真好
You made it so easy.
讓我無後顧之憂
And now you have to leave.
現在你要走了
And I have to live with a boy!
我得跟一個男生住了
It's gonna be fine.
不會有事的
Now I can't wait to live with you!
瑞秋，我真希望你趕快搬進來
You know what we should do?
而且我們應該
Bring Monica, and we'll live together! We'll have so much fun!
把摩妮卡也帶來 我們一起住 一定會很好玩
I think she's moving in with Chandler.
但是她要跟錢德住
Oh,that's right. You're still set on that?
也對 你還是要跟他住嗎？
Kind of.
應該吧
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
How's the packing going?
摩妮卡，打包順利嗎？
Ben? He's fine. He's right.. Oh, my God!
班？他很好，他就在…媽呀
Get your head out of your shirt there, son!
把頭從衣服裡伸出來
Yeah, it's a pumpkin. I'll come pack.
什麼？ 對，是南瓜，我過去幫忙
-What's wrong?  -Ross and I were helping pack...
怎麼了？ 羅斯和我幫忙打包
took a little break. I lost $1500 to him in Cups!
在休息時 我跟他玩杯牌輸了1千5
How did you lose at Cups?
玩杯牌怎麼會輸？
The same way you lost!
跟你輸的方式一樣
I started out with the king and the queen. Bam! Ross gets a 2 and a 3.
我先拿到老K和皮蛋 砰！羅斯拿到2和3
Then I get a jack and a king. Boom! Ross gets a 4 and 5.
然後我拿到傑克和老K 砰！羅斯拿到4和5
Even Ross was getting the Cup card, the D Cup...
羅斯拿到滿杯，D罩杯
the sitting-down bonus. I didn't even get half a cup! Nothing!
和自動加碼 我連半副杯牌都湊不到
Oh,man!
天哪
He never played before either.
他之前也沒玩過
I think beginner's luck is very important in Cups!
我覺得玩杯牌都靠新手的牌運
Let's play one more hand. One more hand.
好，我們再玩一把
No more! I cannot lose another dime. I'm serious this time.
不要，我1毛錢也輸不起了 我是說真的
In fact,look.
事實上
I wanna give you something.
我要送你一樣東西
Let me give it to you before I pawn it for Cups money.
現在先送 免得我為了賭債拿去當
I want you to have the big,white dog...
我要把大白狗送給你
as a thank-you for being such a great roommate.
謝謝你這些年來的照顧
I can't take the big white dog. You love it.
我不能收，你很喜歡這個雕像
It's "him." Not "it."
他不是雕像，他是活的
What if I bought it from you?
要是我跟你買呢？
Then your nice gesture would be giving it to me at a reasonable price.
你可以以合理的價格賣給我
Say $1500?
1千5如何？
Wait a second. I see what you're trying to do here.
等一下，我知道你想幹嘛了
You're trying to give me money again!
你又想塞錢給我
When did I try to give you money?
我什麼時候塞錢給你了？
Over there with the bills!
之前看帳單的時候
You tried to give me charity, I said no, you dropped it.
你想施捨我 我說不要，你也就算了
We had a nice last night together.
然後我們開心度過最後一晚
We had some fun,we gambled,nobody tried to give anybody any money.
說笑，賭錢，誰也沒塞錢給誰
Now you start with the charity thing again!
現在你突然又想來這套
I'm trying to help you out. I wanna make sure that you're okay.
我只是想幫助你 我想確定你的生活沒問題
I will be okay.
我會沒問題的
You gotta get it out of your head that I can't take care of myself.
你不能老覺得我無法照顧自己
I'm not gonna miss you helping me out with money.
我不會懷念你借錢給我
The only thing I'm gonna miss...
我唯一會懷念的...
is you.
就是你
And now the dog.
現在還有這隻狗
-Call me when you get there,okay? -Okay.
到了打電話給我，好嗎？ 好
I'm really gonna miss you.
我真的會很想你
I have your key.
鑰匙要還你
-Here you go. -Thanks.
拿去 謝謝
God,this is silly. I'll see you in a couple of hours.
天哪，多好笑 再過幾小時就會見面了
Bye,house.
房子再見
再見
-She really left. -I know.
她真的走了 我知道
-Thank you. -No problem,roomie.
謝謝你 不客氣，室友
-Can I ask you a question? -Sure.
我可以問你一個問題嗎？ 當然可以
What the hell is that dog doing here?
那隻狗怎麼會在這裡？
I invented the game of Cups as a way to give Joey money.
我捏造了杯牌好塞錢給喬伊
-And now you want that money back? -Exactly.
現在你想把錢要回去 沒錯
What kind of idiot do you take me for?
錢德，你以為我是白癡嗎？
It's not a real game. I made it up.
沒有那種牌，那是我捏造的
I'm sorry you lost your money. But I won it fair and square.
很遺憾你輸錢 但我贏得光明正大
At a fake game!
遊戲是假的
If you wanna try to make some of it back...
如果你想贏一點回去
I'd be glad to play you for it. But I should warn you.
我願意陪你玩 但我必須警告你
I am very good at Cups.
我是杯牌高手
I assume the saucer card came up when you played last.
好，你上次玩 有出現杯盤牌吧？
Let's see if it comes up this time.
看看這次會不會出現